Madhavi Patel

Lansdale, PA 19446 • 267-421-9854 • Madhavip122@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/madhavip93 • https://madhavip93.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Energetic and creative marketing candidate focused on positively impacting business goals and improving customer relations. A team player with top-notch communication skills, strong ability to solve problems, experience in social media, and a desire to continually learn and advance my abilities and skills within the field of Digital Marketing and CRM.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Marketing

Concentration in New Media and Communications Southern New Hampshire University December 2020

Graduated with Honors

Bachelor of Science

Elementary Education Pre K-4th Penn State University December 2016 Graduated with Honors

KEY SKILLS

- Google Analytics
- Content Marketing
- Google Ads Certified
- Microsoft Office Suite
- CRM (NetSuite)

Wordpress

- Graphic Design
- Canva
- Adobe Spark
- Wix, Mail Chimp, Hootsuite

EXPERIENCE

CRM Data/Marketing Specialist

Veterinarian Recommended Solutions

April 2021 - Current

- Designed hundreds of email and physical mailing campaigns to drive attendance to in-person and online conferences, sent to 1000's of contacts with a 70% open rate.
- Researched and coordinated remote events such as "Wine Tasting", "Ice Cream Making", and "Paint & Sip".
 Ensured items were delivered to each participant and collected data on participation. Resulted in significant conversions to sales.
- Developed and posted daily social media posts for Facebook, LinkedIn, Instagram.
- Analyzed results of conferences to spot trends or assess the response to different products, presented to the Leadership Team.
- Improved the quality of the database by cleaning customer contacts in Netsuite, helping Sales and Marketing teams better target potential clients.

Digital Marketing Intern

June 2020 - August 2020

Onpoint Success

- Constructed social media content and email campaigns through Hootsuite/Mailchimp. Sent to 400 users/day with an average open rate of 55%.
- Created custom social media posts featuring testimonials, viral content, blogs, and informational graphics.

Digital Marketing Intern

June 2019 - August 2019

Holiday Inn Express & Suites

- Responded to reviews on social media and third party websites to promote brand loyalty and collect insightful ideas to satisfy customers.
- Analyzed click through rate for booking website and tested improvements to increase number of bookings; led quarterly presentations to share results.

Public Relations, Marketing, and Communications Intern

June 2018 - August 2018

- Researched marketing software solutions and presented results to the leadership team.
- Created the company's first press kit and added it as a new page on the company's website through Wix.
- Developed and posted daily tweets and Facebook posts to Company's social media platforms.
- Created blog content through Wordpress to increase SEO and inform customers about the company.

Instructional ParaProfessional

September 2017 - April 2021

Skippack Elementary

- Analyzed student academic progress and created reports with graphics, work samples, and reports for administrators on a weekly basis.
- Utilized data from standardized exams to guide instruction and intervention.
- Utilized software such PowerPoint, Flipboard, and iMovie to create lessons that are visually appealing and provide necessary information in a memorable way.